# Matthew Laws

Bo6 Barton House, College Road, Sutton Bonington, LE12 5RD Mobile: 07474831416 | Email: matthewjlaws@gmail.com | Git: github.com/PartScottish

### **ABOUT**

I am a recent First Class Computer Science MSc postgraduate from the University of Nottingham, following on of Bristol. I focused on data analysis and, crucially, its visualization in both simple and complex forms using a range of languages such as Python, R, Java and HTML. I have a deep passion for scientific communication and using my skills to assist in the comprehension of complex topics through simple yet effective visualisations. I have extensive experience working with members of the public through my work in the NHS over four years

### **EDUCATION**

### UNIVERSITY OF NOTTINGHAM, UK

#### MSc Computer Science

September 2020 - September 2021 First Class Award (Distinction) Master of Science (1 year) Modules Included: Data Visualization, Designing Intelligent Agents and a Research Thesis

### UNIVERSITY OF BRISTOL, UK BSc Zoology

September 2016 - July 2019 Second class honours - Upper Division Bachelor degree (3 years) Modules Included: Computational Methods, Ecology, Conservation Biology, Animal Behavior and Behavioral Ecology

### UNIVERSITY OF DERBY, UK Access to Higher Education

### DIPLOMA

September 2015 - July 2016 Biology (AA), Chemistry (A)

## RAWLINS COMMUNITY COLLEGE

### **GCSE**

September 2006 - July 2008 12 GCSEs ranging from A\*- B, inc. Maths, Science and English

### **FDUCATION**

### UNIVERSITY OF NOTTINGHAM | COMPUTER SCIENCE MSC

September 2020 - September 2021

from my Zoology BSc at the University of Bristol. I focused on data analysis and, crucially, its visualization in both simple and complex forms using a Distinction special feature (First Class). The MSc modules I took focused on R, JavaScript, HTML and Python and led to successful projects in modules such as Designing Intelligent Agents, Information Visualisation and my Research Thesis.

My projects included an interactive website that visualises a large WHO data set on COVID-19 cases (R, JS, HTML, CSS), designing path-finding algorithms and executing them on a personally designed intelligent environment (P) and also designing and creating an entire small indie game (P).

My Research Thesis (P) focused on supervised classification from text in the context of psycho-therapeutic transcripts. The turns of the patient-clinician conversations were transcribed and labelled with a therapeutic process. The goal of this thesis was to develop the best machine learning algorithms to predict label assignments to turns along with assessing the efficacy of data augmentation techniques at improving predictions.

#### UNIVERSITY OF BRISTOL | ZOOLOGY BSc

September 2017- July 2019

My final year research project was investigating the effects of varying exposure levels of imidacloprid pesticide on Bombus terrestris' (bumble bee) foraging behavior. As a co-lead role, I developed time management and independent working skill sets to ensure deadlines were met and the ability to delegate tasks to others and ensure their completion.

Between my second and third year at university I worked with professor Gareth Jones where I successfully designed, executed and wrote a detailed scientific report demonstrating bat populations throughout three varying habitats in Pembroke. The goal of this project was to identify and monitor what species were present and the plasticity of their sonar design.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### NHS | MEDIC/EMERGENCY CARE ASSISTANT

August 2013 - September 2016

- Worked under pressure to deliver urgent medical attention.
- Developed exceptional teamwork skills whilst working closely as part of a multidisciplinary team.
- Excellent communication skills with the public and emergency care providers.
- Provided training for new medics to ensure their safety driving emergency vehicles.

### NHS | HEALTHCARE ASSISTANT A&E

February 2012- August 2013

- Unparalleled progress in prioritising. Prioritised patients efficiently and effectively based on the urgency of their reason for using the service.
- Undergone non-clinical management training including risk assessment and incident reporting.
- Excelled in organisation and orchestrated emergency clinician schedules with incoming patients.
- Achieved exceptional teamwork skills through multidisciplinary and dynamic teams.